ABHISHEK GUPTA

Language Skills: English (Fluent), Hindi (Native) Visa Status: Stamp 2 Visa Holder in Ireland agabhishekgupta69@gmail.com +353 (0) 89 953 4895 https://www.linkedin.com/in/abhishek-gupta-06a256129/

Profile Snapshot

Abhishek is soon completing his MSc. in Business Analytics from the National University of Ireland, Galway, Ireland. Before moving to Ireland for his master's education, he was working with Flip Robo Technologies (India) in 2021 as a Data Science Intern after gaining experience in the field of sales analytics in a start-up called Techjockey Infotech Pvt. Ltd. (India). Since then, he has been strengthening his skills to become complete analytics professional. In his previous positions, he had experience in working with different statistical programming languages such as R and Python to build the sales structure model of the company, and tableau for creating interactive dashboards and visualization. His previous professional exposure has helped him to master the agile working approach in a team.

Work Experience (most recent first)

01/2021 - 07/2021 Flip Robo Technologies, Bangalore, India

(7 months) Designation: Data Science Intern

Job Activities:

- To analyze and visualize the data provided by the company through clients.
- Making Machine Learning Models predict the accuracy of the client's sales dataset.
- Web scrapping for various projects likes to analyze the market trends of a product listed on amazon.
- Making various NLP Projects, learned how to perform a deep learning model.
- Creating text analysis models using NLTK, and Keras libraries.
- Dusting the primary data to process the data as per the modeling needs.
- Create interactive dashboards on Tableau and visualize the same.

05/2021 – 06/2021 The Sparks Foundation, a Singapore-based organization

(2 months) Designation: Intern Data Science and Business Analytics

Job Activities:

- To learn more about data analysis tools and their use in a real dataset.
- Involved in various projects on different datasets provided by the company (GitHub Link below).
- Used predictive tools in business analytics that can help companies make better decisions.

05/2019 - 07/2020 Techjockey Infotech Pvt. Ltd., Delhi, India

(> 1 year) Designation: Sales Executive/Sales Data Analyst: SaaS Products (promoted in 4 months of joining the company)

Job Activities:

- Developing and driving the sales deal, cultivating relationships with customers and channel partners to the end sales pipeline through CRM of HubSpot.
- Conducted Root Cause Analysis of problems or issues faced by the customer, and partner side presented to various stakeholders, CFO, and CTO of the company.
- The first one in the team to introduce OEM's supported technology for software demos on the company website which increased sales by 18% in just 3 months.
- Understanding regulatory business requirements and performing detailed analysis of complex business
 process requirements to provide appropriate system solutions in collaboration with departments such as
 compliance, product, and pricing.
- Analyze marketing leads, customer interaction on the website, and sales data in Python to analyze the customer behavior and storytelling as per the defined SLA.
- Work for dual side approach mechanism to take feedback from customers and partner team to enable continuous improvement and innovation in products & services.

Skills

Technical

Python, Lucid Chart, IBM SPSS, Microsoft Power BI, R, SQL, Advanced Excel., Tableau, MySQL, C#.

Other skills

Stakeholder portfolio management, Business case development, Channel-partner relationship, Customer support, KPI management

Educational Qualification (most recent first)

09/2021 – 06/2022 National University of Ireland, Galway, Ireland. (Masters Education) MSc. in Business Analytics; Grade 2:1 in First Semester

Main Modules: Database Systems (MYSQL), Business Applications Programming (C#), Decision Theory & Analysis (Tableau), Statistical Techniques for Business Analytics (SPSS), Business Modelling & Analytics (MS Excel, Advanced Excel, Solver, XLMiner), Systems Development & Project Management, Information Systems Strategy, and Innovation, Information Systems Security & Ethics, Enterprise Systems, Advanced Applications Programming (Python, QlikView), Data Science & Big Data Analytics (Big Data, Hadoop) and Applied Customer Analytics (R Programming).

08/2020 – 07/2021 DataTrained Analytics Academy, Delhi, India

(Postgraduate PG Program in Data Science, Machine Learning, and Neural Networks

Diploma) Grade: 76 % (first-class honors)

Main Modules: Advanced Excel, Python (from beginning to advanced level), Machine learning models through python, NLP, Image Classification models, and deep learning models on google Collaboratory.

08/2016 - 07/2019 Jagannath International School of Management, Delhi, India

(Bachelor of Education) Bachelor of Business Administration; Grade: 79% (first-class honors)

Main Modules: Principles of Management, Business Economics, Financial and Management Accounting, Business Mathematics, Marketing Management, Statistics, Operations Research, Production, and Material Management.

Projects

1. Information Systems Strategy and Innovation - Design Thinking Challenge

Collaborated with Mr. Anthony Ryan from SAP Ireland and Prof. Christopher Collins. Design Thinking Challenge allowed us to think critically and create an idea/prototype that will add value to the stakeholders. Designed a layout of an application that can help provide the best experience of Galway culture.

2. Enterprise systems- ERP Consulting

Analysis of Loan application and screening systems and redesign process model. Also worked on a case study related to ERP Change Management, handling RFP, etc.

3. Data Science and Big Data Analytics- Market Basket Analysis

Market Basket Analysis using Excel, Python, and Tableau. Extensive cleaning of raw data, preprocessing, and transformation to build visualizations that help businesses understand the customer buying trends.

4. Major Project- Spotify Song Popularity Prediction

CRISP-ML(Q) process model for machine learning applications with a quality assurance methodology, that predicts the future song popularity based on different attributes such as Artist name, popularity, number of listens, etc. Tools: Python, Tableau, XLMiner, R, Microsoft Power BI, Excel.

5. More projects on https://github.com/abhi6953

Additional Courses and Certifications

- · Applied Machine Learning with Python by IBM.
- · Advanced SQL for Data Science: Time Series
- · Tableau for Beginners by Great Learning.
- · HubSpot Agency Partner Certification.
- · Google Analytics for Beginners.